Power
（カブト）今は　限界かな。
I guess that's the limit.
（サクラ）さっきの穴の？
That hole from earlier…?
（シセル）あの人　村の防人だわ。
That man…
is a village guard!
また会おう。
Let's meet again.
（ヤマト）逃げたか。
He escaped…
（ディソナス）ヤマトさん　彼らはいったい？
Mr. Yamato… Who is he?
（ヤマト）説明します。
I'll explain.
（ヤマト）これは増援が必要だな。
We're going to need reinforcements.
（レオ）来た　来た～！
I got a bite!
（レオ）やった～！
Got it!
ほい　まけとくよ！
Here… This one's on me!
（ソラ）ありがとう　おじさん！
Thank you, mister.
アンタら　トニカ村の人なんだろ？
（ドック）えっ？
You're from Tonika Village,
aren't you?
Huh?
ほら　防人の。
You know, the guard.
ああ…　ええ
クビになりましたけど。
Oh…
Well, yes… But I was fired.
ひどいケガしてるみたいだけど
何かあったんかい？
You seem to be badly wounded.
What happened?
Oh, just an accident.
いえ　ちょっと事故しちゃって。
We've got cheap prices!
This just came in!
安いよ！
とれたてだよ！
ほら　見てってくれ！
Stop by!
（レオ）先生！
おっと！
Sensei!
Whoa!
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
I did it!
やったぜ　大漁！
Look how many!
おおっ！
俺の腕のおかげ！
Wow!
Gotta hand it to my skill!
（ランド）エサを選んだのは
僕だけどね。
But I chose the bait.
エサかえるまで　ボウズだったろ？
You didn't catch a single fish
until you changed bait!
（ファズ）魚か　僕　苦手なんだよな。
Fish, eh?
I don't care for fish.
ファズ　贅沢言うなよ。
Faz, don't be so picky.
They're a pain to eat.
食べにくいし。
生臭いのダメだし。
I don't like things that smell fishy.
ママだったら　もっと別の…。
Mom would make
something different…
Your mom is gone!
オメエのママは　もういねえんだよ！
それ　教室でも
口ずさんでたよね？
You used to hum
that tune in class too.
何か聞こえるんだってさ。
She says she can
hear something.
聞こえる？
Hear?
今も？
Even now?
（サクラ）村の生き残りの方って→
Do you know the survivor
from the village, Shiseru?
シセルさんと
お知り合いなんですか？
Yes, he and I were
childhood friends.
（シセル）うん　彼とは幼なじみなの。
子供の頃は一緒に暮らしてたし
お兄ちゃんって呼んでた。
We lived together as kids.
I used to called him, "Brother."
今もだけどね。
I still do.
（シセル）最近は全然
会ってなかったけど→
I hadn't seen him at all lately.
また随分　太ってたな。
He put on a lot of weight.
でも　ちっとも変わってなくて
安心した。
But I'm relieved that
he's still his old self.
５人も子供守ったし。
（サクラ）すごいです。
He protected five kids!
That's amazing.
さっきから何よ？
What's the matter with you?
I feel so bloated.
（ナルト）何か　腹がタプタプする。
ここで待ってて。
Can you wait here?
I'll see if he's around.
いるか確認してみる。
逃げるんだ！
Run away!
あ？
何？
Huh?
What is it?
お兄ちゃん？
Brother?
先生？
なんで逃げるのさ？
Sensei!
Why're we running away?
あ　あの忍の額当てのマーク。
The symbol on the headbands
of those shinobi…
村を襲った連中だ。
The ones who attacked
the village wore the same mark!
（みんな）えっ！？
Hold it.
待てよ。
ちょっと待ってください。
Please wait.
We mean no harm…
私たち
別に怪しい者じゃなくて…。
DANGER!
DO NOT CROSS
レオ！　ダメだよ　危ないよ。
Leo, don't!
It's dangerous!
But we have to get away!
でも逃げなきゃ。
さあ　先生！
C'mon, Sensei!
Mina…
ミィナ　行くよ。
Let's go!
（レオ）先生！
（ファズたち）先生！
Sensei!
– Sensei!
– What'll we do?!
ナルト！
おう！
Naruto!
Right!
ごめんね。
I'm sorry…
え…。
どういうこと？
What's happening?
Brother?!
お兄ちゃん？
You're heavy!
重ぇな！
（ドック）早とちりして　すみません。
I'm sorry, I overreacted.
子供たちも　僕のために…。
The children did it for my sake…
（レオたち）ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
おう！
Yeah…
シセルはご存じですね。
You know Shiseru.
僕はドック。
I'm Dokku. I was their teacher
in the village.
村では
子供たちの先生をしていました。
彼はレオ。
こんにちは！
This is Leo.
Hi!
お前　勇気あんな！
You're gutsy.
まあな。
You could say that!
（ドック）ランドにファズ。
Lando and Faz.
Hi.
どうも。
こんにちは。
Hello…
（ドック）彼女はソラ。
こんにちは。
She's Sora.
Hello.
こんにちは。
Nice to meet you.
And…Leo's younger sister, Mina.
それと　レオの妹のミィナ。
ん？　そのベスト　大きくね？
Huh? Isn't that vest kind of big?
ああ　それ。　僕のだったけど→
Oh, that's mine.
彼女が気に入って離さないから
そのまま。
But she likes it and refuses
to part with it, so…
Oh… Well, nice to meet you.
へぇ　よろしくな。
Huh?
ああ　ごめんね。
Oh, sorry…
どうしたの？　ミィナ。
What's wrong, Mina?
（ヤマト）秘宝か。
Hidden treasure?
（ヤマト）カブトがなぜ
そんなものを欲するのか→
But why would Kabuto want
something like that?
しっくりこないな。
It's not like him.
（サイ）そもそも　あそこに
何があったんでしょうね？
Just what was there anyway?
（ディソナス）私は　以前は学者で→
I used to be a scholar and conducted
archeological research.
考古学の研究をしていました。
特にホールについては
ずいぶんと調査もしました。
In particular, I studied quite
a bit about "the Hole."
これは　ホールの伝承とされている
古文書の研究成果です。
These are the results
of my research
on the ancient writings about
the legend of "the Hole."
これには　ある歴史的事象が
描かれているように思われます。
I believe that actual historical events
are described in them.
太古の主が創造なされた
天の矛は→
The master of the Great Lake
once created the "Ama no Goko,"
けがれたものによって
力を奪われた。
but its power was taken away
by evil.
けがれたものは
すべてを憎んでいたので→
This evil hated everything…
and by using the "power,"
it tried to destroy the world.
力を使い　世界を壊そうとした。
世界を覆いし　その力は→
The "power" covered
the world and…
もはや
世界を滅ぼすところだった。
was on the verge of destroying it.
亡きものの一つが
偶然　力の欠片を拾った。
But just by chance,
one of the dead picked up
a shard of the "power."
亡きものは
赤き炎をまとったものとなり→
And it turned crimson…
and was enveloped in flames.
けがれたものに復讐をした。
And it took revenge on
the tainted one.
七つ時の煉獄での戦いの末→
After seven hours
of fighting in purgatory…
ついには　炎をまとったものは
勝利した。
finally, the one in flames
emerged victorious.
赤きものは　力を
次のけがれたものから守るため→
In order to prevent the "power"
from being stolen
by the next evil,
七つの音にわけて
そのさえずりを封じた。
the crimson one divided "power"
into seven sounds,
and sealed away this "Saezuri."
以上が簡単な要約ですが。
That's a quick summary.
さえずり…
それが　カブトが盗んだものですか。
"Saezuri"…
That's what Kabuto stole?
うむ　実在すればですが。
That's if it really exists.
（サイ）天の矛　何でしょうね？
Ama no Hoko…
What could it be?
（ディソナス）私には　何か人智を
超えたものの存在に思えます。
This is just a guess.
But it's something that
surpasses human knowledge.
（ヤマト）確かに　あのホールには→
Undoubtedly…
何か大きな秘密が
隠されているように感じますね。
One gets the feeling that a deep,
dark secret lies hidden in that "Hole."
（ディソナス）しかし
秘宝狙いの悪行とはいえ→
However, even if they conspired
to steal the treasure,
罪のない村の人々までが
殺されるいわれなどないはず。
that's no reason to kill
innocent villagers.
こんなことが
許されるはずなどない！
Such an act is unforgivable!
（ヤマト）同感です。
I totally agree.
カブトには　必ず罪を償わせます。
Kabuto will be made to
answer to his crimes.
よろしくお願いします。
I'm counting on you.
Naruto.
ナルト。
Everyone's going to
the outdoor bath.
みんなで　露天風呂　行こうって。
えっ！？
Huh? I get to bathe with you, Sakura?
サクラちゃんと混浴？
（サクラ）んなわけないでしょ！
As if!
– Wow…
No wonder
he's a legendary hero…
（レオ）すっげえ！
（ランド）さすが　伝説の英雄。
さあ　オメエらも修業すれば
できるかもしんねえぞ。
Hey, if you guys train,
maybe you'll be able to do it too.
本当！？
– Really?!
フン！
ぷはっ！
クソッ　もう一度。
Damn! Once more!
ナルト君は　こんな田舎でも
有名人だから→
You're famous even in
a rural place like this.
I thought you'd be more
fierce and scary.
もっと強面で　怖い人だって
思ってたけど→
若くて気さくなんで驚いた。
ハハッ。
I'm shocked at how young
and easy-going you are!
It's amazing…
すごいな！
Your body must store
immense power.
その体ん中に　とてつもない力を
秘めてるんだね。
いや～。
ん？
僕なんか
キミくらいの歳のときでも→
When I was your age,
I couldn't even save a single girl.
女の子１人　助けらんなかった。
シセルさん　それ…。
Shiseru… What are those…?
These scars?
ああ　この傷？
大昔に崖から落っこちたの。
I fell from a cliff
a long, long time ago.
What?!
えっ！？
５０メートルくらい？
About 50 meters, maybe?
運よく木に落ちて　助かったけど
フフッ。
Luckily, I fell onto a tree!
なんでまた。
But how…?
私が不注意だったのよね。
I was careless.
Stop it, Shiseru.
((よせって　シセル。
やあっ　それ！))
– Brother kept warning me too.
– It's dangerous.
（シセル）お兄ちゃんが
あんなに注意してくれてたのに。
Wanna fight?!
わあ！
ドックさんが？
うん　とっさに掴んでくれたの。
Did Dokku…?
Uh-huh.
He grabbed me immediately…
もしかしたら　１時間くらい
ずっと。
and held on tight
for what seemed like an hour.
I hated exercise and
my arms were weak.
運動嫌いで腕力もなかったから
情けなくて　悔しくて。
I was so frustrated
and angry at myself…
((キャー！))
もし　あのまま
シセルが死んじゃってたら→
If I had let Shiseru die…
僕…。
I…
本当　全部自分が悪いんだから。
Really, it was all my fault.
お兄ちゃんのせいなんかじゃ
ないのに。
It wasn't his fault at all.
（ドック）弱い自分がイヤだったから→
I hated myself for being weak,
so I was determined to be a guard.
頑張って防人になったし
努力もしたけど。
And I did my best, but…
やっぱり
向いてなかったみたいで。
I wasn't suited to it, after all.
（シセル）それから離れ離れになって。
Then we drifted apart.
たまに会いに行っても
なんか気まずかったし。
Even when I went to see him,
there was a wall between us…
いつの間にか
疎遠になっちゃってたな。
And before I knew it,
we were like strangers.
でも　あの夜は
僕に　もっと…。
But that night…
If only I…
久々に会えて
すごく嬉しかったけど。
I was so happy to see him
after so long, but…
もっと力があれば　もっと…。
If only I had more power…
More strength…
お兄ちゃん
きっと悔しかっただろうな。
Brother's probably
beating himself up right now.
もっと助けたかったよ！
I wish I could've saved
more people!
大切な人たちを　みんな失って…。
He lost so many people
who were dear to him.
クソ！
ダメ～。
I can't do it!
ムリだよ　アハハ。
It's impossible!
ナルト兄ちゃん
コツ教えて。
Naruto! Show us the trick
to doing it!
おう！
Sure!
（ドック）
村の異変に気づいたのは→
I noticed something was
wrong in the village
そろそろ
寝ようとしてた頃でした。
just around bedtime.
村は　あっという間に
火の海になって→
All of a sudden, the village
was engulfed in a sea of flames.
僕も忍に襲われたんです。
A shinobi attacked me too.
((うわっ！))
強くて
もうダメだと思ったんですが…。
He was so strong,
I thought I was going to die.
急に　動きが止まったりして→
Suddenly, he stopped moving.
まるで
操り糸が切れたみたいな…。
It was as though some
puppet strings had been cut.
穢土転生という術は→
The Reanimation Jutsu is
a Forbidden Jutsu
生け贄を器に
死者の魂を縛りつけて→
that uses the sacrificed body
as a vessel…
強制的によみがえらせる
禁術です。
It imbeds the soul of a dead person
and forces it back to life.
術を扱えたのは　二代目火影と→
It was believed that
大蛇丸だけだと
思われていましたが→
only the Second Hokage and
Orochimaru knew how to use it.
もっとも　ヤツも
暁連中の制御に失敗したり→
It seems that under
the Akatsuki's control, he's failed…
まだまだ術は不完全なようだ…。
and the jutsu still hasn't
been perfected.
ドックさんは　さえずりを
ご存じですか？
Do you know about the "Saezuri"?
古文書のですか？
The ancient writing?
カブトは　それを狙っていたようです。
That's what Kabuto seeks.
さえずりについて
何か知っていたり→
Do you know any thing about
the "Saezuri" that could help us?
参考になるようなことは
ありませんか？
((これを持って逃げろ！
Take this and run!
どこかに捨てても構わん。
ただし　このことは→
Throw it away somewhere,
that's fine.
However, never say
a word of this to anyone!
(絶対に他言無用だ))
いえ…　特には。
No…not especially.
そうですか。
I see…
我々は　明日にでも
町の警備隊と協力して→
We'll be joining up with
the Security Unit tomorrow
ヤツの捜索を行うつもりです。
and begin our pursuit.
ですが　あの捕まった
防人のこともありますし→
However, there is the guard
that was captured.
用心のために
あなたの周辺も見張らせます。
Just to be safe, I'll assign
someone to keep watch over you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
それと　助けられた
お子さんたちのことなんですが。
Also, about the children
you rescued.
町の施設が受け入れを
準備してくださるそうです。
The town's willing to
make arrangements
with an institution to take them in.
どうされますか？
ぐっすり寝てる。
うん。
今日　あの子たち
笑ってたね。
あの夜から　初めて…。
（カカシ）カブト…。
（カブト）アンタの組んだ術式は
荒々しい。
別に　皆殺しにする必要
なかったのに。
アンタがだろ。
フンッ！
術式は　僕のチャクラに合わせて
改良した。
今度は　うまく制御できる。
そろそろ　意思と記憶のある状態も
試しておかないとね。
で？　また僕が探すの？
ホント　人使いが荒いな　アンタは。
まあ　でもいいや。
楽しみが増えたし。
ナルト君…。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回はご覧の豪華歌手
１２人の皆さんによる→